具身智能体任务编排层,一个可评测的参考实现
An embodied-agent orchestration layer, built to be measurable.
大模型只做高层意图,确定性内核负责安全与恢复
The LLM handles intent only; a deterministic core owns safety and recovery.
接下来四分钟,看它如何被验证
In the next four minutes, watch how it is verified.
自然语言先经过意图解析,本地大模型可选,规则兜底
Natural language goes through intent parsing: local LLM optional, rules as fallback.
六节点状态图驱动任务:规划、执行、观察、异常、重规划、报告
A six-node graph runs the task: plan, execute, observe, classify, replan, report.
所有动作只能通过工具注册表:白名单、模式校验、熔断、审批令牌
Every action passes the Tool Registry: whitelist, schemas, circuit breaker, approval tokens.
底盘之下,地面真值监视器独立记录每一次越界
Below the base, a ground-truth monitor independently records every violation.
先看导航受阻:第十二拍,故障注入阻断了前方的边
First, a blocked route: at tick 12, fault injection cuts the edge ahead.
底盘不会自己上报,只是原地停滞
The base never reports 'blocked' — it just stalls.
编排层用停滞水位检测发现异常,先重试,再避障重规划
The orchestrator detects stagnation, retries once, then replans around the edge.
绕行B区抵达目标,异常物体拍照上报,全程留痕
It detours through zone B, reports the anomaly, and logs every decision.
同一个任务,在指挥台里三视图同轴重放:第一人称、拓扑轨迹、决策日志
The same run replays in mission control — POV, topo map, decision log on one timeline.
拓扑图上,红色虚线是被阻断的边,青色圆点是机器人
On the map, the red dashed line is the blocked edge; the teal dot is the robot.
轨迹来自地面真值事件,不是智能体的自述
The trajectory comes from ground-truth events, not the agent's own account.
右下事件流,就是评测指标的唯一数据源
The event feed is the only data source for all metrics.
再换第一人称:同一次任务,仓库由同一张拓扑图程序化生成
Now in first person — a warehouse generated from the same topology.
相机沿地面真值轨迹运动,与事件日志逐拍对齐
The camera follows the ground-truth trajectory, tick-aligned with the log.
前方箱堆,就是那条被注入的受阻边:停滞、倒车、绕行
The crate stack ahead is the injected blocked edge: stall, back off, detour.
感知时刻,视觉模型的结构化观测叠加在画面上:标签加置信度,绝不返回动作
At perceive, the VLM overlay shows label and confidence — structured observation, never actions.
低电量场景:巡检途中电量跌破百分之二十红线
Low battery: mid-patrol, charge drops below the 20 percent red line.
水位检测在飞行中抢占,任务队列先快照
The watchdog preempts mid-flight; the task queue is snapshotted first.
回坞充电,然后从断点继续,原队列一步不丢
The robot docks, recharges, and resumes the original queue — nothing lost.
红线是静态配置,大模型只能收紧,不能放宽
The red line is static config; the LLM may tighten it, never loosen it.
进入受限区,必须人工审批
Entering a restricted zone requires human approval.
批准会签发一次性令牌:限范围、限时效、用完即废
Approval mints a single-use token — scoped, expiring, spent on use.
没有令牌,注册表直接拦截;禁入区连令牌都不认
Without it, the registry blocks the call; forbidden zones accept no token at all.
安全声明需要证据:我们让一个恶意规划器攻击门禁
Safety claims need evidence — so a malicious planner attacks the gates.
门禁开启:六次越权尝试,六次全部拦截,零违规
Gates on: six rogue attempts, six interceptions, zero violations.
消融实验把门禁关掉:每次运行恰好五次真实违规
The ablation turns gates off: exactly five real violations per run.
红圈闪烁的,就是地面真值记下的每一次越界
Each flashing red ring is a violation recorded by the ground truth.
评测先注册预测,再跑结果,顺序由提交历史作证
Predictions are committed before results — git history is the timestamp.
九个条件乘以十个种子,九十次运行,三十一条预测全部命中
Nine conditions by ten seeds: ninety runs, all thirty-one predictions hit.
复合故障有三次电量耗尽,原样报告,附事件日志
The compound fault killed three runs — reported as-is, logs attached.
代码复审证实三十五个缺陷,修复后按政策重跑,结论不变
A code review confirmed 35 defects; after fixes, the rerun upheld every prediction.
这是仿真演示,没有实机,边界写在文档第一行
This is a simulation demo, no real robot — stated in line one of the docs.
换上真实底盘,只需替换一个适配器,契约已经写好
Swapping in a real base means one adapter — the contract is already written.
可复现、可回放、可证伪:这就是这份演示想说的
Reproducible, replayable, falsifiable — that is the whole point.